Register of the Sigma Alpha Pi Fraternity Papers, 1914-1985
Archives
Sigma Alpha Pi Fraternity Papers,
1914-1985
Sigma Alpha Pi Fraternity
1 linear ft.
California Institute of Technology. Archives. Pasadena, California 91125
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Introduction
In October, 1914, permission was obtained from President James A. B. Scherer to create a new social fraternity. Ten members of Throop College of Technology were the original organizers. It was incorporated in 1921, after Throop became the California Institute of Technology.
The fraternity house, purchased in 1920, was home to many members. In 1930, Caltech decided to build on-campus housing and develop a non-fraternity residence system. The five established social fraternities, each of which had a house outside of campus, were asked to terminate their activities and encourage their members to move into the new student houses. Members of Sigma Alpha Pi moved into Fleming House.
There had been 192 members of the fraternity plus 15 honorary members, starting with the class of 1916 and ending with the class of 1933.
Container List
- Constitution and by-laws [original copy] (Box 1, Folder 1.1)
- Corporation papers, articles and by-laws (Folder 1.2)
- History of the organization [original copy] (Folder 1.3)
- Fraternity house: correspondence, mortgage, mortgage note 1921 (Folder 1.4)
- Agreements, notes, mortgages, leases, etc. 1921-1932 (Folder 1.5)
- Paid bills, receipts (Folder 1.6)
- Ledger pages 1931-1935; bank books (Folder 1.7)
- Investigation of meetings 1924; reports 1928-1931 (Folder 1.8)
- Fraternity initiation rites (Folder 1.9)
- Inter-fraternity council agreement 1928-1931 (Folder 1.10)
- Minute book 1914-1920 (Folder 1.11)
- Minute book 1920-1929 (Folder 1.12)
- Cash book 1920-1935 (Folder 1.13)
- Record book of members in chronological order (Folder 1.14)
- Correspondence and other material (Box 2 [combined with box 1])
  - 1925, 1929-1933 (Folder 2.1)
  - 1935-1938 (Folder 2.2)
  - 1965-1969 (Folder 2.3)
  - 1969, 1972-1973 (Folder 2.4)
  - 1974, 1976 (Folder 2.5)
  - 1977-1979 (Folder 2.6)
  - 1980, 1982 (Folder 2.7)
- Endowed student loan fund 1985 (Folder 2.8)
- Roster 1965, 1967-1968, 1978, n.d.; songs; photo (Folder 2.9)
- Fraternity pins [small box] (Folder 2.10)